[EREN TITAN growls]
[EREN] I can win.
I can beat Reiner.
He's going down!
[Bellows]
[CONNY]
Huh? No, no, no, no, no!
[MALE SOLDIER 32A]
Above you! Look out!
[SOLDIERS groan]
[BOTH groan]
[MIKASA grunts]
[SOLDIERS scream]
[ALL grunt]
[Roars]
[REINER TITAN growls]
[Gasps]
Eren!
♪ Opening Song ♪
[PYXIS snoring]
[ANKA]
Ugh.
You're kidding me.
Wake up, Commander.
You'll catch your death
sleeping out here.
Tell me you didn't
drink all this yourself.
God. Sir, please.
Keep tossing it back like
someone half your age,
I'll end up
putting you in diapers.
Doesn't sound so bad to me.
Old men like to be doted on.
What's the situation?
Well, several patrol
units were sent out.
Not many Titans
between the first
and second defensive lines.
And the few that did crop up
seemed like they
were pretty far apart.
[PYXIS]
Hmm.
If Hannes and the
advance squad have managed
to follow the wall
without incident,
they should be getting
back before too long.
Fairly straightforward
operation.
They'd have run into
the unit from Krolva
about halfway and
turned around for home.
It's a safe assumption they
encountered few Titans, if any.
If Wall Rose
had been breached,
sightings wouldn't be so random.
[ERWIN]
Commander Pyxis.
[PYXIS]
Hm?
Ah, Commander Erwin.
Is it true what I hear
about you catching
a troublesome little mouse?
Well... technically, yes.
Not that it's helped us.
Hm. Well, at least
those goons in the interior
might start using their heads.
Might even be forced to
reconsider their belief system.
Morally bankrupt as it is.
[ERWIN]
Agreed. Seems they have.
Look over there.
Military Police
putting in an appearance
where Titans aren't just
an academic problem.
[MALE SOLDIER 33A]
Damn. Can't believe
we didn't see one.
You really sayin'
there weren't any?
I know, right?
It's unusually quiet out there.
Wonder if
they're still alive.
What a joke.
I thought this was
s'posed to be an emergency.
Yeah. We just come here
to sit on our asses, or what?
Hey Levi! Where you
hidin' all the Titans?
Problem?
You seem eager to be
eaten alive, solider.
[ALL gasp]
[LEVI] Huh. Sorry we
couldn't make that happen
for you today.
Plenty of opportunities
outside the wall
if you're lookin'.
Lots of scouting expeditions.
I'd be more than
happy for the help.
We could all
fight Titans together.
Well, you know.
There's our work
in the interior, so...
[MALE SOLDIER 33E] Hey!
The advance squad is back!
Go! Tell Commander Pyxis!
[PHIL panting]
[PYXIS] I see. No breach as far
as you could tell, correct?
[PHIL]
That's correct, sir!
[PYXIS]
Mmm. As I thought.
But, sir! A situation
has developed!
You see, we ran
into another group
on the way back to Trost.
It was the Scout unit led
by Section Commander Hange.
There were recruits
from the 104th Cadet Corps
with them, none of whom
had equipment.
This may sound crazy, sir,
but three of them
were Titans!
--[SOLDIERS gasp]
--What the--? Hang on sec.
Seriously? You mean like
there were three... more?
But... who were they?
Who, damn it?
Actually, I, um...
Jean, calm down.
What happened when their
Titan forms were revealed?
The Scouts engaged
the Armored Titan
and the Colossal in battle
as best they could, sir!
But by the time our unit
arrived on the scene
it was... too late.
I'm sorry.
[footsteps]
[HANNES sighs]
Oh, man. What a mess.
Count your lucky stars
we were all the way up here.
Rest of 'em got blasted
by steam and debris;
nothing much they could do.
How badly is Mikasa hurt?
Well there aren't
any wounds to speak of.
I think it's just a concussion.
Could be worse.
[HANNES] Armin, I've got
food if you're hungry.
You eaten?
[HANNES]
Be right back.
[Indistinctive chatter]
[ARMIN panting]
[ARMIN]
Mikasa!
[Panting]
Come quick!
Eren's in trouble!
What kind of trouble?
It's those
three bullies again.
They took the bread
I just bought.
I--I told Eren about it and--
I didn't want him to go!
Wait!
Give it back.
You have dirt in
your ears or somethin'?
Like I said, I already
ate the whole thing.
Tasty.
But that was three days
worth of food for them!
You gotta be kiddin' me.
Those table scraps?
Knock it off.
You'll make me feel bad.
Whatever, you want it
back so damn much--
--[Imitates retching]
--[BOY 33C, 33B laugh]
Pay him back
what the bread was worth!
[Grunts]
Whoa! What are you doing?
Hey! There's a
situation over here
if you hadn't noticed!
Get off your drunk asses!
Ugh, come on. They're just
kids bein' kids.
Let 'em work it out.
[MALE MERCHANT 33A]
They're demolishing my stall!
[BOY 33A grunts]
This, uh, ain't our thing.
Best wait for someone
more qualified
to come along and sort it out.
Huh?
Eren!
Eat this, punk!
[BOY 33A groans]
[Yells]
[ALL laugh]
Mikasa--!
I've got this.
What are you doing?
Eren, you need to
go home and chop wood.
You want your mom to get angry?
You little--
Now it's a fight!
[BOY 33B]
You asked for it--!
No! It's okay!
She can handle it!
Let go!
[Yells]
Oh-ho! Nice one!
Don't let her
do all the work!
[Groans]
What was that for?
Don't cheer
the little bastards on!
Damn freeloaders!
Freeloaders? D'you just
call us freeloaders?
Hey, if the shoe fits,
shove it up your ass!
You son of a--!
Hey. Hey!
He's got a point, y'know.
--I mean--
--[MALE MERCHANT 33A grunts]
[Laughs] Heh.
That's some right arm.
For a chump who runs a stall!
[BOY 33A yells]
[Groans]
[SPECTATOR 33A]
Yeah! Get him, Hannes!
[SPECTATOR 33B]
Come on, man!
Don't get beat by a soldier!
[MILITARY POLICEMAN 33A]
Stop it right now!
What the hell
is wrong with you?
Act like adults!
[EREN]
Give it back!
[Chuckles]
Damn it!
[MILITARY POLICEMAN 33A
whistles]
That's enough!
Uh-oh. Hey, guys?
This is gettin' kinda serious.
Screw this!
We're outta here!
Get back here!
--Where d'you think you're--
--[ARMIN] No, Eren!
I don't care about
the stupid bread!
Let it go!
That's enough.
We're going back home
right this instant.
Like hell! Go without me!
Eren! Wait!
[MILITARY POLICEMAN 33A]
No you don't!
[MIKASA]
Hold on! Eren!
Eren!
[Exhales]
[Gasps]
Mikasa.
Where is Eren?
Where did he go?
Whoa! Calm down!
Wait! You shouldn't--!
We don't know
how badly you're hurt!
Where is he?
Eren and Ymir were taken.
They're gone. Reiner and
Bertholdt abducted them.
He fought, but the
Armored Titan was just too--
[ARMIN] That was
about five hours ago.
Somebody's gone
after them, right?
Tell me somebody
went after them.
--I'm sorry.
--[MIKASA] Why not?
We wanted to,
but the horses
are on the
other side of the wall.
Our only option is to wait.
The mounts can't be hauled over
until the lifts make it here
and that takes time.
There's nothing else
we can do right now.
Section Commander Hange
and the other officers
are too injured to move.
We don't have enough soldiers
to form a scouting party.
Even a small one would
need more than this.
We're not experienced enough.
You understand?
Damn it. Not this again.
You feel any pain?
No. I hit my head,
but I think I'm okay now.
Don't worry about it.
It's just...
...not the first time
I've been down this road.
Except when Annie took him,
I didn't waste
a second. Not one.
That's how Captain Levi and I
were able to get him back.
But... it's already
been five hours.
[MIKASA]
Hey, Armin.
Why's he do it? Always leave?
Always end up
someplace we're not?
Yeah, it does
seem to happen a lot.
Ever since we were kids Eren
liked to run off on his own.
Leave us worried sick.
Who knows? That's just
the sort of person
he's meant to be. Maybe.
[MIKASA]
I don't want much.
Just to be near him.
That's all.
[HANNES]
Good. You're awake.
Must be starving. Here.
Heads up, Armin.
Sorry it's only field rations,
but better than nothing,
I guess.
[HANNES]
Not bad. Not good either.
Nothing new there.
Aaah.
Speaking of which,
this feels familiar, huh?
You two've been
runnin' damage control
for that little hothead
since the good ol' days,
if I recall correctly.
Doesn't seem very fair,
but what do I know?
Different time, different
place, same problem.
Not exactly what I'd call
a healthy relationship.
Am I wrong?
[Chuckles]
The neighborhood bullies
weren't quite so tall,
but I suppose
there are similarities.
Yep. That's our Eren. Heh.
Can't hold his own for shit,
but always lookin' for a fight.
Five guys wanna take him on,
he'd wouldn't think twice
about jumping into
the fray like an idiot.
By the time
Mikasa gets there
or the MPs show up,
he's beaten all to hell.
But you know...
I may not've ever had the
privilege of seeing Eren win,
but I never saw the little son
of a bitch back down either.
Kid's got fire.
To tell the truth,
his persistence scares
the piss outta me sometimes.
He gets knocked on his ass,
he gets right back up again.
It's in his blood.
You think he'd let himself
be snatched away
without fighting
tooth and nail?
Not a chance.
Whatever strength
he's got left, he'll use it.
What's two guys
next to a whole gang?
If you can count on anything,
it's that Eren'll give 'em hell.
At least till you
or me shows up to help.
That's how it's
always been, right?
[MIKASA gasps]
[ARMIN gasps]
Yes, sir. Those good ol' days
were somethin' else.
'Course if you ask Eren,
he'd tell ya
they were an illusion.
Just us kidding ourselves.
But I for one was
never happier than when
folks thought of me as
a freeloading waste of space.
There's not much
I wouldn't do to get us back
to how things used to be.
Call me sentimental.
But I'm willing
to fight for it.
He needs us.
Whaddya say
we stick to what we know.
It ain't the good ol' days 'less
the three of you are together.
[ARMIN grunts]
[MIKASA grunts]
[HANNES grunts]
They're here.
Is that?
Oh, wow.
[MOBLIT]
Ah!
Commander Erwin!
[MALE SOLDIER 33G]
With MPs!
[ARMIN] Never thought they'd
ride on top of the wall.
Probably the
quickest route here.
For the record,
I know you won't,
but I'd much prefer it
if you stayed behind.
No, not happening.
Nice try, though.
As long as Ymir's in danger,
nothing will keep me here.
Sorry. That's just how it is.
[CONNY] We're all
in this together, Armin.
You're not special.
Every one of us
has a reason for going.
Still trying to
process mine, to be honest.
I have to know why
Bertholdt and Reiner
did what they did.
I wanna ask while I
look them dead in the eye.
[Horse neighs]
Good to see you,
Commander Erwin.
Glad you're here.
Is the situation
still the same?
--Yes, sir.
--Good.
Right! Deploy the lifts!
[MOBLIT shrieks]
Hange?
Don't just stand there.
Gi-Give me a map.
[HANGE] It's a gamble,
but the trees in this forest
are massive. I say
we ride straight for it.
See, even if
they had a way to cover
the Armored Titan's footprints,
this is almost definitely
where we would find them.
Why's that?
[HANGE]
They need to recoup.
They have the power
to assume Titan form,
but other Titans on that side of
the wall still pose a threat.
Especially after
putting up such a fight.
Yes, Eren was the worse for it,
but they've got to be spent.
Remember when Annie
went out cold?
Let's suppose they're headed
somewhere beyond Wall Maria.
That's not a simple hike.
They'll need all
the rest they can get
before covering
that kind of distance.
They're in no shape
to make it in a single push.
And if so, they'll want
to catch their breath
somewhere other Titans
can't get to them.
Odds are they'll
hold out till it gets dark.
[REINER]
You're awake.
Welcome back.
[HANGE]
We have until sundown!
[HANGE] If we can
reach the forest by then,
we might just have
a chance to save them!
[ERWIN]
Let's move!
♪ Closing Song